# **Andrew R. Jones**

**★** andrewrayjones.com **♀** Austin, TX **▲** andrewrayjones@gmail.com **in** jonesan2 **♠** jonesan2

## **Profile**

I'm a full-stack software engineer with experience in the Ruby and JavaScript ecosystems along with AWS, Docker, and Golang. I co-created Gander, an open-source review app solution that automatically deploys a full-stack preview application with every pull request.

## **Experience**

## **Co-Creator & Software Engineer,** Gander

2021

gander-framework.github.io 🛮

- Designed and built overall system architecture, spanning GitHub, Amazon Web Services, and the Gander CLI
- Designed AWS infrastructure, researching features and evaluating tradeoffs with respect to ECS Fargate, Amazon Elastic File System, load balancers, and public vs. private subnets
- Automated creation and transformation of AWS infrastructure with bash scripts and GitHub Actions
- Designed the review app build process, leveraging GitHub Actions, Docker, and Cloud Native Buildpacks
- Led routing implementation, using AWS application load balancer, target registration, and CNAME records
- Led writing and testing of demo application
- Defined problem space and researched market space for drop-in review app solutions
- Authored technical case study exploring Gander's design challenges and solutions

### Software Engineer, Self-Employed

2018 - 2021

- Cello: Trello-like collaboration app built for MongoDB with a Node/Express backend and a React/Redux frontend
- RequestTub: React/Express app for capturing and monitoring webhooks, built using Socket.IO and with PostgreSQL storage
- Todos: Sinatra todo management app, built for PostgreSQL and using Erb

#### **Teacher, Advanced Physics & Engineering, Hays CISD**

2013 - 2021 | Buda, TX

- Teacher of the Year Nominee; selected 14 times by a student from the Top 10% as their most influential teacher
- Launched high school robotics program; Coached UIL state finalist robotics team

#### **Skills**

## Languages

JavaScript, Ruby, SQL, HTML, CSS, Go

## **AWS Cloud**

Amazon VPC, Amazon ECS, AWS Fargate, Elastic File System (EFS), Elastic Container Registry (ECR), Application Load Balancer, IAM, AWS CLI, CloudFormation

#### **Frameworks**

React.js, Express.js, Sinatra, Ruby on Rails

## **Technologies**

Docker, Git/GitHub, GitHub Actions, Cloud Native Buildpacks, HTTP, WebSocket, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, REST APIs, Redux, Heroku, Handlebars, Erb, Shell Scripting

#### **Education**

**Launch School** 2020 – 2021

Multi-year mastery-based learning curriculum for software engineering | launchschool.com/employers 🛮

Ph.D., Hebrew Language and Literature, University of Toronto

2008 - 2015 | Toronto, Canada

M.A., Christian Studies, Regent College

2004 - 2007 | Vancouver, Canada

**B.S., Computer Engineering, with distinction,** Purdue University

1997 - 2001 | West Lafayette, IN